Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Art and Art History, Honors Theses
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Stanford University, Department of Art and Art History, honors theses
1997-2014
SC4-3594
Stanford University. Department of Art and Art History.
1.25 Linear feet (13 volumes in 3 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Department of Art and Art History.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Information about Access
The collection is open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Dept. of Art and Art History.
Access Terms
Art--History--Study and teaching.; Art--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Theses, Accession 2011-152
  - Blanchard, Emily S., Ambivalent anti-Semitism: the invocation and transformation of Jewish stereotypes in John Singer Sargent's portraits of the Wertheimer family., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Breeden, Jenny, Jean Dubuffet: on the question of Post-War creativity and criticism [2 volumes]., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Chiles, Alisa, Reason, iron, and the age: the significance of Hector Guimard's organic rationalist architecture., 2007 (Box 1)
  - Corn, Melanie, Feminist artists take to the streets: guerrilla tactics of the 1980s., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Eagleston, Alisa Rae, The Virgin, Child, and Saint John: conserving and attrributing a Renaissance panel painting., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Field, Allyson Nadia, Jean-Luc Godard and Guy Debord: revolutionary cinema and the cinema of the revolutionary., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Hertenstein, Tom, The shock of the real: modern monoliths and the aesthetics of plain power., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Richmond, Camilla Ann, The culture of color: Winslow Homer's watercolors as a prism of the social., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Kim, Jeaannie, Pulp fantasies: the amazing and weird imates of Virgil Finlay., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Tai, Ariella, Der West, a study of the East German Westerns., 2009 (Box 1)
  - Waggoner, Diane, Sounding the thread: the interlace of needlework and the feminine in Victorian painting and narrative., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Liu, Emily, Love, illness, aesthetics: responding to Eugene Richards' Exploding into life., 2007 (Box 2)
- Theses, Accession 2015-039
  - Hart, Jordan Campbell, The Guggenheim effect, controvery, expansion, and finance within the Solomon R. Guggenheim Foundation., 2014 May 15 (Box 1)